# **SARAH BERRY**

Accomplished web and print designer with a strong graphic design background and a long, successful track record in project management and client relations. Experienced with all stages of the development process for dynamic web projects. Well versed in several CMS platforms with a keen eye on performance and accessibility.

401.368.1379

sb@sarahberryresume.com

DIGITAL PORTFOLIO SITE www.sarahberryresume.com

#### **EXPERIENCE**

FREELANCE WEB DESIGNER | OCT 2017 - CURRENT

Motif Magazine — Pawtucket, RI

Overseeing and executing UI improvements to an array of WordPress sites associated with the magazine.

SENIOR DESIGNER | OCT 2009 - SEPT 26, 2017

### Envision Technology Advisors — Pawtucket, RI

Responsible for designing and developing web sites and interactive marketing materials such as landing pages, forms, online promotions and other marketing materials as requested in a fast-paced environment. Duties included HTML and CSS hand-coding, graphic design, UI design, and coordination with other internal development teams.

- Established and maintained new and repeat client design accounts.
- Directed regular client and internal staff meetings to ensure project goals and timelines were on target.
- Produced custom signage, banners, guest name badges and gift packages used at Marketing and Sales events.
- Redesigned logo, marketing materials and collateral for Concord OBGYN which gave rise to a new practice image and elevated their brand to a more elegant feel.

FREELANCE WEB DESIGNER | MAY 2007 - OCT 2009

#### Self Employed — Pawtucket, RI

Built a variety of ASP and PHP sites designed by Project Evolution in Providence RI and Solo Designs in Winchester MA. Designed, built and maintained sites for several of my own personal clients including Learning Links Educational Services, Chestnut Hill Studios, and several local artists and craftsman.

WEB DESIGNER/DEVELOPER/GRAPHIC DESIGNER | JUL 2001 - MAY 2007

# Envision Technology Advisors — Providence, RI

- Architected web projects and online apps from initial discovery and planning through wireframing, design, build, QA, deployment, and client training using ExpressionEngine as our primary CMS platform.
- Worked closely with marketing teams designing corporate logos & print pieces ranging from large-scale trade show graphics to corporate identity packages unifying our customers' online and offline aesthetics.
- Also designed for and heavily participated in running and planning a successful online marketing campaign for Amica Insurance.

### WEB DESIGNER/DEVELOPER/GRAPHIC DESIGNER | JUL 2000 - JUL, 2001

#### New Media Advantage — Providence, RI

Designed, built, and maintained corporate sites, many of which were healthcare oriented. Managed a small team of developers, the scheduling of project milestones and coordinated with clients on proposed changes or challenges to be overcome. Designed logos, marketing materials and sales sheets. (*This company was acquired by Envision.*)

WEB DESIGNER/DEVELOPER | SEP 1999 - JUL, 2000

## Metro Global Media Inc. – Cranston, RI

Designed, built, and maintained a large number of websites and online advertising for the "adult entertainment" industry. Collaborated with a team of third-party West Coast software engineers to create user interfaces for their e-commerce products.

#### **PROJECT SAMPLES**

#### Honey Dew Donuts →

Designed and built their public site along with an intranet for employees and franchisees.

#### MTTI - Education for Employment →

Designed their new site to be easy for them to update and to keep their programs current and success stories visually interesting.

# Blackstone Valley Community Health Care →

Redesigned their site to be cleaner, clearer, simple to update and translatable into several languages with an emphasis on ADA Compliance.

#### **SKILLS**

- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- InDesign
- Dreamweaver
- Acrobat
- HTML5
- CSS3
- SCSS

- Git
- Google Analytics
- Balsamia
- ExpressionEngine
- Wordpress
- MailChimp
- Constant Contact
- MS Office

#### **ASSETS**

- Creative Designs
- Responsive Builds
- Search Engine Optimization
- Accessibility/Usability Expertise
- Project & Client Management Skills
- Excellent Communicator
- Complex Problem Solver
- Strong Decision Maker
- Meticulous Attention to Detail

### **EDUCATION**

RISD — BFA '99 Illustration with graphic design concentration. Graduated with honors.